（イノイチ）第４部隊より　連絡。
We just received word from
the Fourth Company!
ダンゾウ様の護衛の暗部が
穢土転生されているとのこと。
Lord Danzo's ANBU bodyguards
have been reanimated.
（シカク）行方がわからなかった
トルネとフーのことか。
You mean Torune and Foo
who were listed as missing?
Probably.
（イノイチ）あぁ　たぶんな。
死んでいたのか。
（イノイチ）あぁ…。
So they were killed…
Yes…
（綱手）２人ともか？
Both of them?
（イノイチ）確認されたのは
トルネだけです。
Only Torune has been confirmed.
各部隊に伝えろ。　見つけしだい
最優先で封印しろ　と。
Notify every company!
He is to be sealed
the moment he is located!
それほどの者なのですか？
Is he that formidable?
油女シクロの子だ。
He's the son of Shikuro Aburame.
穢土転生で操られているなら
禁術を使う恐れがある。
If he's being controlled
through the Reanimation,
there's a horrible possibility
he will use a Forbidden Jutsu.
（綱手）ナルトにも連絡しろ！
Get word to Naruto too!
ダンゾウ様の護衛についた　もう一人…
フーは　どうしたかな？
I wonder what happened to Foo,
Lord Danzo's other bodyguard.
そうか　山中一族の者だったな。
That's right…
He belonged to the Yamanaka Clan.
あぁ　根などに
やりたくはなかったが…。
Yes… I didn't want him to
join the Foundation…
（カブト）どうしたんだい？
What's the matter?
（トルネ）くっ！
禁術だろうが
何をためらう必要がある？
Even if it's a Forbidden Jutsu,
why resist?
Nothing is forbidden anymore.
もう　誰も　何も禁じないよ。
壺毒の術！
Jar of Poison Jutsu!
フフフフ…　細工は流々。
You certainly know your stuff.
仕上げを頼むよ。
I'm counting on you to finish it.
クソ！　この禁術を使うとは…。
Damn it… To be forced to use
this Forbidden Jutsu…
Shino vs. Torune
ん？　よく　ここがわかったな。
Good job finding me…
（シノ）蟲の知らせだ。
My beetles notified me.
お前…　シノか！
You're…Shino?
トルネさん…　トルネさんなのか？
Torune… Is that you, Torune?
あぁ。
Yeah.
その様子から察するに
穢土転生されたのだな。
Based on your appearance,
it seems you were reanimated…
そうだ。
That's right.
つまり
あなたは死んだということか。
Which means…you died.
あぁ　残念だが。
ダンゾウ様は　どうしている？
Unfortunately, yes.
How is Lord Danzo?
死んだと聞いている。
I heard he died.
そうか。
あのあと　マダラにやられたか。
I see…
So Madara killed him after that…
事実関係は少し違うが。
It was not quite like that.
そんなことより
これがなんだか　教えてくれ。
But never mind...
Please tell me what all this is.
壺毒の術だ。
It's the Jar of Poison Jutsu.
壺毒？
Jar of Poison…?
この穴の中で
蟲を急速に培養している。
Insects are rapidly
multiplying in this hole…
Do you remember
my Venomous Beetles?
俺の毒蟲のことは覚えているか？
忘れるわけがない。
I would never forget.
なぜなら　あなたとは
兄弟のように過ごしたからだ。
That's because we grew up together
like brothers.
((アカデミーには　もう慣れたか？
Have you gotten used to
the Academy yet?
まだ　慣れない。
Not yet. That's because
my class is so rowdy.
なぜなら　騒がしいクラスだからだ。
こうして
虫と遊んでいるほうがいい。
I prefer playing with insects like this.
そうもいかないさ。
That won't do.
そのうちお前も
忍として任務に出る。
In time, you will go on missions.
そのとき
友達がいるといないでは大違いだ。
When you do, having friends
and not having friends
will make a huge difference.
トルネはアカデミーに行かなかったのだろ。
Torune, you didn't go to
the Academy, did you?
俺は一族のなかでも特殊だからな。
That's because I'm special
even within the clan.
特殊とは　なんのことだ？
Special in what way?
お前には　そろそろ教えておくか。
I guess it's time I told you.
俺の体のなかには　猛毒を持つ
ナノサイズの毒蟲がすんでいる。
My body is host to…
nano-sized Venomous Beetles
with extremely toxic poison.
俺には　毒への抗体があるが→
My body has antibodies
for the poison.
他のものが感染すれば→
But if any other living thing
is infected,
体中の細胞を破壊されて死ぬ。
the cells in its body will
be destroyed and it'll die.
触るな。　この毒蟲は→
Don't touch it!
These Venomous Beetles
thrive only in living cells.
生き物の
細胞のなかでしか生きられない。
細胞を壊しながら増え　宿主が
死ねば　毒蟲も宿主ともども死ぬ。
They destroy cells as they multiply.
If their host dies,
the Venomous Beetles will also die.
ウイルスのようなものか？
そうだ。
Like a virus?
Yes. These insects can
only survive in my body.
だからこの蟲は俺の
体のなかでしか生きられない。
だから俺は誰にも触らない。
That's why I can't touch anyone.
トルネは　アカデミーに
行かなかったのではなく→
Torune, so it's not that you didn't
go to the Academy,
you couldn't go there.
That's because…
行けなかった。　なぜなら…。
そういうことだ。
You're right.
だが　お前は違う。
But you're different.
早くアカデミーに慣れて友達をつくれ。
You must get used
to the Academy quickly
and make friends.
（ナルト）ピヨーン！
Charge!
Huh?
お前
机に蟲がたかってるってばよ。
Hey, there are bugs on your desk!
（キバ）ホントだ！
かまわないでくれ。
He's right!
Just leave them alone.
なぜなら
これは俺の飼っている蟲だ。
That's because they're my insects.
へぇ～　蟲飼ってんだ。
Oh, so you collect bugs?
普通　飼うなら
カブト虫とかクワガタだろ。
Don't most people collect
rhinoceros beetles or staghorn beetles?
Say, let's throw these bugs
at the girls in class.
なぁ　なぁ　この蟲　クラスの
女の子たちに撒き散らそうぜ。
Wouldn't it be fun watching them
scream their heads off like "eeek"!
キャーッ！　って大騒ぎになって→
おもしろそうだってばよ。
These insects aren't
for that purpose.
これはそういう蟲ではない。
蟲は蟲じゃん。　やろうってばよ。
Bugs are bugs.
Let's do it!
Let's make 'em scream,
like "eeek"!
キャーッ！　って。
（イルカ）なにが　キャーなのかな？
Make who scream?
キャーッ！
Eeek!
I don't understand this thing
about friendship.
友達というものが
よくわからない。
That's because
everyone is so different.
なぜなら
みんなそれぞれに違うからだ。
（トルネ）違っていても　一緒に
過ごせれば　友達じゃないのか。
Even if they're different,
if you spend time together,
aren't they your friends?
それならば　クラス全員が
友達ということになる。
Well then, I'd have to consider
my entire class my friends.
そんなことはない。
It's not like that.
お前は　細かく考えすぎなんだよ。
You analyze things too much.
親父…。
Dad…
（ダンゾウ）あれが　お前の息子か。
（シビ）はい。
Is he your son?
Yes.
根に入れるには
いいころあいだな。
He's at a suitable age
to enter the Foundation.
えっ？
Pardon?
As you know, the Foundation is
where ANBU agents are developed.
知ってのとおり
根は暗部の育成機関だ。
さまざまな人材を
幼いときから鍛えあげる。
Those who show great promise
are selected
when they are still young.
The Foundation is being reorganized
根を再編成するにあたり→
油女一族より
１名出してもらいたい。
and I would like the Aburame Clan
to send us someone.
このことを　三代目は？
Has Lord Third approved this?
根の人材選出は
わしに一任されている。
Selecting recruits to the Foundation
is wholly under my jurisdiction.
山中一族も　うちは一族も→
Every clan that possesses a Hidden Jutsu,
including the Yamanaka and
Uchiha Clans, has sent someone.
皆　秘術を持つ家系は
根に人材を提供している。
しかし　シノは…。
お前の息子ならば優秀であろう。
But Shino is…
He's your son.
He must be exceptional.
何の話なんだ　親父。
What is this about, Dad?
言っておくが
これは要望ではない　強要だ。
Let me make it clear.
This is not a request, but an order.
そんな…。
But that's…
優秀というのなら
俺でもいいんじゃないか。
If he wants someone exceptional,
won't I do?
トルネ。
お前は？
Torune…
And you are?
見たところ
下忍ですらないようだが。
From the looks of you,
you're not even a genin.
俺は　油女シクロの子だ。
I'm the son of Shikuro Aburame.
あのシクロに子がいたのか。
Shikuro had a son?
縁あって　うちで預かっている。
As fate would have it,
we became his guardians.
ほお～　外へは出せなかったか。
You couldn't bring him out
into the open, huh?
おもしろい。
少々とうが立ってはいるが→
Interesting…
He's a bit older than I'd like, but…
この者を　根で預かろう。
the Foundation will take this boy in.
I should tell you…
言っておくが
誰も俺とは組めないぞ。
You can't team me up with anyone.
図にのるな。
Get off your high horse.
You aren't the only one
who knows a Secret Ninjutsu.
秘伝忍術の使い手は
お前ばかりではない。
Come to my place tomorrow morning.
明日の朝　わしのもとへ出向け。
わかった。
Understood.
Torune… Are you sure about this?
トルネ　いいのか？
（トルネ）根に行ったからって
死ぬわけじゃなし。
It's not like joining the Foundation
will kill me.
だが　お前とは
もう会えなくなるな。
But we won't be able to
see each other anymore.
お別れだ。
This is good-bye.
But why, Torune?
どうしてなんだ　トルネ。
Entering the Foundation means
abandoning everything until now,
根に行くということは→
これまでと　これからの
人生を捨てるということ…。
as well as your future.
Thank you!
今まで…。
(今まで　お世話になりました))
Thank you for all you've done.
Those Venomous Beetles
are extremely lethal,
（シノ）その毒蟲は　強力だが
接触感染しかない。
but they can only be
transmitted through touch.
So what is the meaning of this Jutsu?
この術にどんな意味がある？
This Jar of Poison Jutsu requires
a large amount of flesh.
壺毒の術には
大量の肉体が必要となる。
That's why it's considered a Forbidden Jutsu.
それが禁術のゆえんだが
この戦場で十分に手に入った。
But I was able to gather
many from the battlefield.
（トルネ）十分な細胞があれば
蟲は死なずに増え続ける。
With this amount of cells,
the insects won't die.
They'll just keep multiplying
while the decaying flesh releases gas.
死滅した細胞から
ガスを生じさせながら。
I see… So it's the gas...
そうか　ガスか。
（トルネ）そのガスを爆発させ→
And the gas is then ignited…
俺の毒蟲に汚染された細胞を→
the cells carrying
my Venomous Beetles
will scatter and infect everyone
in the surrounding area.
あたり一帯に撒き散らし
接触感染させる。
That's what the Forbidden
Jar of Poison Jutsu is.
それが禁術　壺毒の術だ。
So it doesn't discriminate
between friend or foe.
敵味方　お構いなしということか。
早く味方を呼べ。
Hurry and call for reinforcements.
You won't be able to stop me
by yourself.
お前だけでは　止められない。
No, I'm probably
the only one who can.
いや　たぶん　あなたを
止められるのは　俺だけだ。
無理だ　シノ。　あれから俺は→
It's useless, Shino.
I underwent rigorous training
at the Foundation.
根で厳しい修業を積んだ。
I know that all of you in
the Foundation are skilled.
根の者が手練れだということは
知っている。
I never thought it possible,
思ってもみなかったが→
but I even made a friend
in the Foundation.
根では　友と呼べる者までできた。
Hidden Jutsu! Beetle Sphere!
秘術　蟲玉！
《トルネ：フー》
Foo…
友達は　できたか？
Did you make any friends…
シノ。
Shino?
友達ができたかどうか
わからない。
I don't know if I have friends.
（シノ）なぜなら　向こうが俺を→
That's because I'm not sure if
they consider me their friend.
友と思っているか
わからないからだ。
（トルネ）あいかわらず細かいな。
Always analyzing.
（シノ）物事を正確に
判断しているだけだと思うが。
To me,
it's just judging things accurately.
俺は　根に行って
よかったと思っている。
I think it was a good thing
that I joined the Foundation.
俺の体質では　普通の忍として
普通の任務はこなせない。
With my physical constitution,
I couldn't be an ordinary shinobi,
taking on ordinary missions.
だが　根の暗殺部隊は
俺に向いていた。
However, the Foundation's ANBU
was a good fit for me…
秘伝忍術の使い手として。
As someone who uses
a Secret Ninjutsu.
((ダンゾウ：お前の術は
相手に接触することが基本だ。
Making contact with your opponent
is the basis of your jutsu.
体術の実力が知りたい。
I want to see how good
you are at taijutsu.
このフーと　忍組み手をやってみろ。
Spar with Foo.
しかし　俺の体には…。
But my body is…
（フー）ダンゾウ様から話は聞いている。
Lord Danzo has told me about you.
（フー）直接
素肌に触れなければいいんだろ？
The main thing is to avoid
touching your skin, right?
それに　キミは
俺に触れはしない。
And besides,
you won't be able to touch me.
なんだと？
What did you say?
キミは　今日
根に来たばかりの新米だ。
You just entered the Foundation today.
俺と一緒にするな。
クッ！
Don't think you're my equal.
始めろ。
Begin.
だぁ～！
それでガードしたつもりだろうが…。
You call that being on guard?
俺が本気だったら
お前　もう死んでるぞ。
If I were serious,
you'd be dead by now.
ダンゾウ様が知りたいのは
今のお前の実力だ。
Lord Danzo wants to know
your true strength.
本気を出してもらわないとな。
You have to fight seriously.
Come on!
口ばかりだな。
You're all talk.
見せてやれ。
Show him.
はっ。
Yes, sir.
たぁ！
そら。
うわっ！
There you go.
Hold it right there!
そこまで。
クソッ！
Damn it!
今後　お前たち２人に
ツーマンセルを組ませる。
From here on,
you two will form a cell.
フー　トルネに根のことを教えてやれ。
Foo, teach Torune about
the Foundation.
はい。
コイツと！？
Yes, sir.
With him?
(心転身の術と
毒蟲の術の連携は使えそうだ))
The Mind Transfer Jutsu
and the Venomous Beetle Jutsu
should work well together.
お前
フーが　どうしたか知らないか？
Do you know what happened to Foo?
知らない。　２人は行方不明に
なったと言われている。
No, I don't.
You were both listed as MIA.
そうか…　フーもどこかで
穢土転生されているのかもな。
I see… Maybe Foo's also
been reanimated somewhere.
その報告は受けていない。
We have no reports about that.
シノ　俺の昔話に　なぜ　つきあう？
Shino, why waste time listening
to me ramble about my past?
You haven't called for help.
誰も呼びに行かないが
俺をどうやって止めるつもりだ？
How do you intend to stop me?
I know you're trying to buy time.
時間稼ぎだとは　わかっている。
なぜなら　蟲の培養に
まだ時間がかかるからだ。
That's because the insects require
more time to multiply.
You intend to die together
with me.
相打ち覚悟だろうが
それは無理だ！
But that's futile!
俺に接近戦を仕掛けるな！
Don't attempt close combat with me!
蟲が使えない以上　これしかない。
If I can't use my beetles,
this is the only way.
誰か遠距離タイプを呼んでこい。
封印術者もだ！
Then get someone who's skilled
in long-distance combat.
As well as a Sealing Jutsu User.
I don't know of anyone who
fits that description right now.
そんな知り合いは　今いない。
シノ！
Shino!
お前　ナルトか？
You're…Naruto!
Yeah, but I'm a clone.
分身だけどよ。
I came over 'cuz
I sensed your chakra.
お前のチャクラを感じて来てみたんだ。
あれが
本部から連絡のあったヤツか。
Is that the guy HQ sent
messages about?
よくお前が
俺のチャクラとわかったな。
I'm impressed
you recognized my chakra.
It's from my training.
修業の成果だってばよ。
いや　そうではなくて。
No, I didn't mean it that way.
Shino, don't let him attack recklessly.
シノ　うかつに攻撃させるなよ。
I just have to pulverize him, right?
とにかく　ぶっ倒せばいいんだろ？
ぶっ倒せば毒蟲が飛び散る。
If you do that,
the Venomous Beetles will scatter.
それに相手は　穢土転生だ。
封印しなければダメだ。
Besides, our opponent is
a Reanimation.
We have to seal him.
それと　あの人に触れるな。
毒蟲に感染する。
Also, don't touch him,
because his Venomous Beetles
will infect you.
触れるばかりではない。
Not only by touch…
Poison Cloud Jutsu!
毒塵の術！
フッ！
Get away!
And definitely, do not inhale.
逃げろ！　絶対に吸い込むな！
触れたり吸い込めば　こうなる。
ナルト　お前　封印術はないのだな？
That's what happens if
you touch him or inhale it.
Naruto, don't you have a Sealing Jutsu?
あ…　ああ。　お前はあるのか？
No. Do you?
封印札は持たされている。
I've been given Sealing Tags,
but I have no way to apply them.
だが　これを貼り付けるすべは
今のところないな。
その札を捨てろ！　シノ！
Get rid of those tags, Shino!
俺は　邪魔者を
排除しなくてはならない。
I'll be forced to destroy anyone
who gets in my way.
体が勝手に攻撃を仕掛ける！
My body will attack on its own.
I won't let you lay a finger on Shino.
シノには指一本　触れさせねえ！
俺が動きを止めてやる！
I'll stop your attacks!
指一本　触れてはならないのは
ナルト　お前だ。　なぜなら…。
Naruto, you're the one
who can't lay a finger on him.
That's because…
なぜならはいいよ　シノ。
I get it, Shino.
気をつけろよ　人柱力。
根で仕込まれた暗殺術。
Watch out, Jinchuriki.
The Assassination Jutsu
of the Foundation…
知るかよ！
Like I care!
チッ…。
グアーッ！！
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
はっ！
ダメだ！
No!
食らうな！
Get away!
ナルト。
Naruto!
シノ！！
Shino!
あ…　ああ…　クソ！
Damn it!
人柱力　俺を倒せ。　封印しろ！
Jinchuriki, take me down! Seal me!
そうでなければ　俺は　このまま…。
Otherwise, I'll continue to…!
おい…　大丈夫か？
Hey, are you all right?!
下がってくれ　ナルト。
えっ…　お前…。
Get back, Naruto.
Huh? You're…?
From here on, as Insect Users,
let's settle this just between us.
ここからは
蟲使い同士でかたをつける。
お前　いったい　どうして…。
俺の毒蟲が触れたはずだ。
Shino, how in the world…?
I know you touched
my Venomous Beetles.
毒蟲が触れたのは
この俺の蟲たちだ。
Your Venomous Beetles
touched my beetles.
あなたは
俺の兄のような人だった。
You were like
an older brother to me.
あなたとの思い出がわりに
俺は　あの毒蟲を飼育した。
I wanted a keepsake from you,
so I nurtured and bred
those Venomous Beetles.
エサに俺の蟲を与えて育て続けた。
I raised them by feeding them
my beetles.
何年も何世代も
育てているうちに→
Several years later,
after many generations of offspring…
毒蟲に抗体を持つ蟲が生まれた。
beetles with antibodies against
the Venomous Beetles were born.
それが　この蟲だ。
They are those beetles.
With the antibody, they won't die
抗体を持つ　この蟲は
あなたの毒蟲に触れても死なない。
even if they come in contact
with your Venomous Beetles.
蟲使いとはいえ　そんな特殊な蟲を
携行などしないはずだ。
You may be an Insect User,
but no one can host
such a unique insect…
ましてや　これだけの数などは。
Especially not in this quantity.
ああ　常に連れ歩いたのは
１０匹程度だ。
Yes, I carried about ten with me.
それを　この場で培養させた。
Then I made them multiply here.
術の結界のせいか
計算よりはやく済んだ。
Maybe it's the effect of
the jutsu barrier,
but it took less time
than I calculated.
シノ　お前は…。
Shino, you're…
((時間稼ぎだとは　わかっている。
I know you're trying to buy time.
(なぜなら　蟲の培養に
まだ時間がかかるからだ))
That's because the insects
require more time to multiply.
相変わらず　細かいな。
You never skip a detail.
昔ほどではない。　なぜなら
もう　一人ではないからだ。
But not like before.
That's because I'm not alone anymore.
Forgive me, but I must seal you.
すまないが　封印する。
You don't need to apologize.
お前が謝ることはない。
なぁ　この中
どうすりゃいいんだ？
Say, what do we do
about all this inside the hole?
Don't worry.
The Jutsu User has been sealed away.
大丈夫だ。　術者が封じられた以上
蟲は　やがて死滅する。
Eventually, these insects will die.
けりは　ついたんだな？
So it's all over?
行ってくれ　ナルト。
キバやヒナタが向こうにいる。
Please go, Naruto.
Kiba and Hinata are over that way.
おう。
Right!
トルネさん　感謝する。
Torune, I'm grateful to you.
俺は　根に行かなくて
よかったと思っている。
I'm glad I didn't have to
join the Foundation.
なぜなら…。
That's because…
おい！　オメエは　どうすんだよ。
早く来いよ　シノ！
なぜなら　友ができたからだ。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。